# Jose R. Velazquez Gonzalez

🗣 Victoria, British Columbia 🖿 joserobertovg@gmail.com 🔲 (778) 700-6364 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/joservelazquez/ 🛥 https://analystjose.com/

#### **SUMMARY**

Fast-learning data analyst with 12+ years experience in diverse businesses, developing unique insights from operations to management. Enthusiastic about processing, analyzing, and interpreting data to identify key metrics to drive growth, using tools such as R, SQL and Tableau. Strong business acumen and outstanding communications skills to create and present accurate reports and visualizations.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: SQL, R, Python

Software and Technologies: Tableau, Tableau Prep, RStudio, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Excel, Jupyter Notebooks, Office 365

Languages: Advanced English, Native Spanish

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Online Sales Specialist**

Vetta

March 2020 - Present, Remote

- · Designed Tableau dashboards to perform a business analysis and present findings to stakeholders, focusing on Sales and AR.
- · Built e-commerce stores (Shopify and Mercado Libre) including layout, themes, descriptions, images, and prices for 200+ products.
- · Delivered prompt customer service on Messenger, WhatsApp, and e-mail; reducing response times to less than 1 hour.

#### **Operations Auditor**

Coppel

January 2017 - August 2019, Zacatecas, Mexico

- · Analyzed individual store operations from the database to select unusual and/or suspicious operations to prevent fraud.
- · Performed retail stores, warehouses, and distribution centers audits, evaluating performance and generating auditing reports.
- · Reviewed processes, receipts, documents, and inventories to generate a proper risk assessment for managers to make better decisions.

#### **Insurance Agent**

**Seguros Monterrey New York Life** 

July 2015 - January 2017, San Luis Potosi, Mexico

- $\cdot \text{Arranged meetings evaluate individual clients' needs and goals to create long-term savings, investing, and retirement plans.}$
- · Explained in detail each individual policy coverage as per the current law of insurances and sureties.
- · Certified insurance agent in Mexico by CNSF (National Insurance and Surety Commission).

### **Customer Service Specialist**

Telcel

December 2013 - March 2015, San Luis Potosi, Mexico

- · Delivered outstanding face-to-face customer service, sales, quotation, billing, problem solving and client retention.
- · Managed confidential information of hundreds of customers, creating and updating information on ERP.

## **Proprietary Trader**

Self-employed

December 2011 - Present

- · Traded diverse CFD's (Forex, Indices, Commodities, Futures, and Crypto) using a rule-based system with proper risk management.
- · Used technical analysis including price action, market structure, moving averages, support and resistance, and supply and demand.

### **Administrative Assistant**

**Atena Bienes Raices** 

August 2009 - August 2013, San Luis Potosi, Mexico

- · Processed documents, collected client information, and filled out loan approval forms with banks and government agencies.
- · Created and updated an Excel database with hundreds of homes listings, for sales persons to easily access the properties features.

## **EDUCATION**

### Certificate in Business Intelligence and Data Analytics

University of Victoria · Victoria, British Columbia · 2022

## **Certificate in Business Administration**

University of Victoria · Victoria, British Columbia · 2022

#### Bachelor's in Business Administration

Minor in Finance · Universidad del Valle de Mexico · Mexico · 2009